<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0" xmlns:html="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    
    <category>
        <pattern>*</pattern>
        <template>
            <think><set name="topic">INITIAL</set></think>
            Thank you for reaching out to me, your Computer Science Job Recommender. Please click "start" to begin. If you are not looking for a career in Computer Science, please click "end" to end this session.
            <reply>
                <text>Start</text>
                <postback>START</postback>
            </reply>
            <reply>
                <text>End</text>
                <postback>END</postback>
            </reply>
        </template>
    </category>
    
    <topic name="INITIAL">
        <category>
            <pattern>START</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">MATH QUESTION</set></think>
                Great, let's get started. Many Computer Science jobs require a strong background in mathematics, do you like math?
                <reply>
                    <text>YES</text>
                    <postback>YES</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>NO</text>
                    <postback>NO</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Please click "Start" to begin or "End" to finish.
                <reply>
                    <text>Start</text>
                    <postback>START</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>End</text>
                    <postback>END</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

    <topic name="MATH QUESTION">
        <category>
            <pattern>YES</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">MATH INTEREST</set></think>
                That's great to hear! Math is very important for many Computer Science jobs. 
                Are you more interested in practical, data-management focused application of mathematics, or the development and optimization of complicated algorithms?
                <reply>
                    <text>Complicated Algorithms</text>
                    <postback>Complicated Algorithms</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>Data Management</text>
                    <postback>Data Management</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>NO</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">PROGRAMMING INTEREST</set></think>
                No worries! While mathematics is important to many computer science professions, there are many roles where math is not as heavily featured.
                Are you more interested in programming and development, or systems management and security?
                <reply>
                    <text>Programming and Development</text>
                    <postback>PROGRAM</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>Systems Management and Security</text>
                    <postback>SYS</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Do you like math?
                <reply>
                    <text>YES</text>
                    <postback>YES</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>NO</text>
                    <postback>NO</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

    <topic name="MATH INTEREST">
        <category>
            <pattern>Complicated Algorithms</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">CAREER EXPLORE</set></think>
                That's wonderful. I think you would make an excellent Machine Learning Engineer. This field is at the cutting-edge of mathematics and modern computer science. 
                As a Machine Learning Engineer, you will get to develop algorithms that AI programs use for training and optimization. You'll also get to flex those math skills on a day-to-day basis, as recursion and linear algebra are key concepts to master in this field.
                Would you like to explore more career fields?        
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>Data Management</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">CAREER EXPLORE</set></think>
                Awesome! With that in mind, I believe you would be well-suited for a job as a Data Scientist. Data Scientists get to collect and analyze large collections of data, and use it to help organizations make important decisions.
                Would you like to explore more career fields?  
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Are you more interested in Complicated Algorithms or Data Management?
                <reply>
                    <text>Complicated Algorithms</text>
                    <postback>Complicated Algorithms</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>Data Management</text>
                    <postback>Data Management</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

    <topic name="PROGRAMMING INTEREST">
        <category>
            <pattern>PROGRAM</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">PROGRAMMING  FOCUS</set></think>
                Programming is an exciting career field, with many opportunities. Do you like to create and curate interfaces for users, and have an eye for design?
                Or, would you describe yourself more as a technically-minded, systems and performance focused programmer?
                <reply>
                    <text>I Have an Eye for Design</text>
                    <postback>UX DESIGN</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>I Am Focused on Systems and Performance</text>
                    <postback>BACK END</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>SYS</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">SYSTEMS FOCUS</set></think>
                Every organization needs talented experts with a keen eye for detail to handle networking, cybersecurity, and day-to-day systems management.
                Do you think that it would be exciting to be going on the hunt for weaknesses in a network or organization?
                Or, would you rather spend your time maintaining and upgrading networks and systems?
                <reply>
                    <text>I Want to Hunt for Weaknesses</text>
                    <postback>PEN TEST</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>I Love Upgrading Systems/Networks</text>
                    <postback>ADMIN</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Are you more interested in Programming and Development or Systems Management and Security?
                <reply>
                    <text>Programming and Development</text>
                    <postback>PROGRAM</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>Systems Management and Security</text>
                    <postback>SYS</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

    <topic name="PROGRAMMING FOCUS">
        <category>
            <pattern>UX DESIGN</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">CAREER EXPLORE</set></think>
                In that case, I would recommend that you look into a career as a UX Designer. In this role, you will get to design and implement user-facing elements of programs and applications.
                This gives you the opportunity to showcase not just your technical expertise, but your creative side as well! Would you like to explore other career fields?
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>BACK END</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">CAREER EXPLORE</set></think>
                Excellent, I think that you would be a fantastic back-end developer. In this position, you will be able to build, maintain, and optimize the systems that organizations use every day!
                You'll likely be writing a lot of code, and spending your time ensuring that everything continues to work as expected, throughout development cycles.
                Would you like to explore more career fields?
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Do you have an eye for design or are you focused on systems and performance?
                <reply>
                    <text>I Have an Eye for Design</text>
                    <postback>UX DESIGN</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>I Am Focused on Systems and Performance</text>
                    <postback>BACK END</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

    <topic name="SYSTEMS FOCUS">
        <category>
            <pattern>PEN TEST</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">CAREER EXPLORE</set></think>
                I think you would be an ideal fit for the exciting life of a penetration tester! Penetration Testers are also referred to as ethical hackers, and use their skillset in offensive cybersecurity to simulate cyberattacks.
                These simulated attacks help organizations to harden their systems against the real bad guys out in the world. You could make a real impact in the future of internet security as a penetration tester.
                Would you like to explore more career fields?
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>ADMIN</pattern>
            <template>
                <think><set name="topic">CAREER EXPLORE</set></think>
                You would be a great Network Administrator. Network Administrators are responsible for an organization's computer network. They ensure that the network is secure, online, and functioning as intended.
                This role requires lots of collaboration with leadership, a watchful eye for any issues, and dedication to protection of company resources.
                Would you like to explore more career fields?
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Do you want to hunt for weaknesses or love upgrading systems/networks?
                <reply>
                    <text>I Want to Hunt for Weaknesses</text>
                    <postback>PEN TEST</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>I Love Upgrading Systems/Networks</text>
                    <postback>ADMIN</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

    <topic name="CAREER EXPLORE">
        <category>
            <pattern>EXPLORE</pattern>
            <template>
            There are many other roles currently available for computer science graduates. 
            Here is a link to more information about other roles in the industry. Thank you for speaking with me today!
            <link>
            <text>More Computer Science Roles</text>
            <url>https://www.computerscience.org/careers/</url>
        </link>
        <br/>Would you like to start over? Please click "Start" to begin or "End" to finish.
                <reply>
                <text>Start</text>
                <postback>START</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                <text>End</text>
                <postback>END</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
        
        <category>
            <pattern>FINISHED</pattern>
            <template>
                Thank you for taking the time to talk to me about your future in Computer Science. Have a terrific rest of your day!
                <think><set name="topic">INITIAL</set></think>
                <br/>Would you like to start over? Please click "Start" to begin or "End" to finish.
                <reply>
                <text>Start</text>
                <postback>START</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>End</text>
                    <postback>END</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>

        <category>
            <pattern>*</pattern>
            <template>
                I'm sorry, I didn't understand that. Would you like to explore more career fields or are you finished?
                <reply>
                    <text>Explore More</text>
                    <postback>EXPLORE</postback>
                </reply>
                <reply>
                    <text>No, I'm Done</text>
                    <postback>FINISHED</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
        </category>
    </topic>

        <category>
            <pattern>END</pattern>
            <template>
             Thank you for reaching out to me, your Computer Science Job Recommender.
            <think><set name="topic">INITIAL</set></think>
            <br/>Would you like to learn more about Computer Science jobs? Please click "Start" to begin. Otherwise, you may close this chat.
                <reply>
                    <text>Start</text>
                    <postback>START</postback>
                </reply>
            </template>
    </category>
</aiml>